# Abubakar Gudal

# Software Engineer

gudalabubakar@gmail.com + 44 7398 396172 London, United Kingdom

# **Profile Summary**

Adept Software Engineer with proficiency in designing, implementing, and sustaining applications across diverse programming languages. Demonstrated track record in supporting complete project lifecycles, deploying a range of technologies and frameworks. Extensive experience in Agile methodology lifecycles.

## **Professional Experience**

## **Lobby** Software Engineer L

London, UK October. 2021 - August 2022

- Optimised, maintained, and refactored critical application features using JavaScript and React Native, enhancing performance and usability.
- Demonstrated proficiency in developing and managing microservice architectures while effectively navigating isolated development procedures.
- Aided in user interface design, developed and maintained vital backend databases with SQL.
- Integral in developing infrastructure as code, effectively managing project deadlines.
- Promptly resolved production issues, mitigating application downtime.
- Gained in-depth understanding of Agile work environment and team roles. Proactively sought feedback for professional growth and skill enhancement.

## Made By Fire Software Engineer (Intern)

London, UK June. 2018 – August 2018

- Contributed to software development efforts, delivering bespoke platforms for clients.
- Monitored, managed, and maintained test and production environments, optimising for availability, performance, and security.
- Designed front-end and back-end of the app, integrating Google APIs and SWIFT, meeting project timelines.
- Enhanced communication and teamwork skills through participation in daily Scrum stand-ups and Sprint Retrospectives.

# **Project Experience**

## Wrappify Founder and Creator of Wrappify (Full Stack)

London, UK July. 2023 – Present

- Using the SpotifyAPI in conjunction with a React framework, I have developed a distinctive visual representation of user-aggregated data, offering this service promptly.
- Employing JSX, CSS, and JavaScript, I crafted a user-friendly interface while seamlessly integrating Image Recognition capabilities via a REST API.

#### **Novo** Final Year Project (Full stack)

London, UK September. 2022 – June 2023

- Developed a Chrome extension called NOVO.AI, designed to provide second-hand clothes from a fast fashion store using Image Recognition technology (Google Cloud Vision).
- Utilised HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to create a user-friendly interface, and integrated Image Recognition capabilities through REST API.

#### **GoGreen** Full stack Developer (University Project)/Project Manager

London, UK September. 2021 - June 2022

- Constructed a full-stack web application using React, Rest API, MySQL, HTML, JavaScript, CSS.
- Led Agile-based project management, coordinating meetings and assigning tasks.
- Designed a database model for customer and user data storage through Rest API and MySQL.

## Technical skills

Languages: ReactJS, React Native, Node.js Python, HTML, CSS, JS, Java, C, SWIFT

Infrastructure: Linux

Containerization: Docker, Kubernetes

CI/CD: Gitlab CI/CD

Databases: SQL: MySQL, PostgreSQL

Cloud: AWS

## **Education:**

Brunel University London - BSc in Computer Science (2.1 Honours)

Course Skills - Data Structures, Operating systems, Algorithms, OOP in C++, Compilers etc.

Final year project – Chrome extension utilising image recognition to provide sustainable alternatives for fast fashion products.